And now, presenting Mokku, the rarest
wooden puppet in the world, who moves
freely without strings and even sings!
First, Mokku will sing and walk!
Come on, Mokku, sing. Sing!
B-But I don't know any songs!
Idiot, just make something up!
But I...
You bastard, you know what'll
happen if you don't sing!
Come on! That's it, go!
♪ Boku wa kashi no ki, ki no ningyo. ♪
I am an oak tree, a wooden puppet.
♪ Atama no naka made kashi no ki darake ♪
Even the inside of my head is pure oak.
♪ Yarukoto kodomo to kawaranai ♪
Everything I do is just like a child.
♪ Dakedo dakedo ♪
But still, but still,
♪ sabishi toki ni wa namida ga deru yo ♪
when I'm lonely, the tears start to flow.
♪ Boku wa kanashi ♪
I'm just a sad
♪ ki no ningyo ♪
wooden puppet
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
our next act is a delightful puppet
performance: "The Polka Dance"!
Hey, dance!
But... I-I can't dance...
Idiot! Just dance however you want!
But I...
There!
Come on, just like that!
Today was three times the usual crowd.
From now on, I will make a bundle!
Mokku...
I feel bad for him, but he's about to
go through something way worse.
That's right. We puppets are
just playthings for humans.
They work you to the bone, and in
the end, they throw you into the fire.
No matter how terribly we're
treated, it can't be helped.
We've been puppets from
the day we were made.
Grandpa...
Mokku...
Mokku, where did you go?
I'm all alone again...
Please come home, my Mokku.
Grandpa, I'm sorry.
Mokku, have you come to your senses yet?
Didn't I tell you back at the junk shop?
Grandpa is the one you should
feel sorry for, not yourself.
Grandpa's so worried
about you he can't sleep.
He even sold his coat and caught a cold.
And forgetting his kindness
makes you an awful guy, Mokku.
Oh? Did that make you mad, Mokku?
I'm going to work for Grandpa.
Well, I'll be. Where on earth?
I'll work here and buy Grandpa
an overcoat before I go home.
You're so naive.
The world doesn't work that easily.
You'd better give up.
I've had enough of your meddling.
Take my advice, Mokku.
If you trust humans too much,
you'll make a fool of yourself.
Hey, Mokku!
Shut up!
He's gone...
Whatever. Good riddance
to that annoying pest...
Well, if it isn't Mokku!
Um... boss?
What!
Starting tomorrow, I'm going to work
as hard as I can for you, boss!
Well, that's an admirable attitude.
If you're going to be cooperative, it'll
save me the trouble of yelling at you.
In return, though...
What?
I want you to give me
a share of what I earn.
What?!
Take that back!
You little...
I see!
If you're gonna become more popular
and work hard, I've got no complaints.
Fine, I'll give you a cut.
Thank you, boss!
I'll do my best.
Good, good boy. I'll give you plenty,
so go on to sleep now.
Stupid puppet.
Bring out Mokku!
Yeah! Bring him out!
Ta-da!
I'm making a fortune here!
Um, boss!
Got something to say?
About my promised share...
I'm worried about Grandpa,
so please let me go home.
What?!
You idiot!
You think you can leave
after earning this measly bit?
But you promised...
Shut up!
Ah!
Hey!
I never intended to give you
a single penny from the start!
You'll work until you break into pieces!
Understand, you fool?!
Poor Mokku. In the end, we puppets
are just playthings for humans.
Grandpa...
Mokku, just give up. We're puppets.
Humans work us to the bone, and once we
break, they burn us. That's the end of it.
The Cricket was right.
I was wrong.
Ah...
I worked for that money.
It's mine.
If I take it home, I can buy Grandpa an
overcoat and anything else he needs.
Like hell I'll let that monster
boss keep it all to himself!
All right.
Mokku, what are you going to do?
I'm going to avenge everyone.
Stop it, Mokku. Don't you know
how terrifying the boss is?
He'll smash you to pieces
and throw you into the stove!
Don't do it, Mokku.
I'll steal the key to get outside...
Look, it worked.
Mokku, run while you have
the chance. Come on, hurry!
Let's all escape together!
We can't. We can't walk on
our own like you, Mokku.
Don't worry about us.
Get out of here, quick!
No!
All right.
There's no way I'm leaving you
in a terrifying place like this!
Huh?! What? Mokku!
That bastard's trying to run
off after stealing my money?!
Wait!!
Wait, wait!
Gotcha, you little bastard!
No! I worked hard for this money!
You worthless brat!
Now!
Like hell I'll let you get away!
Hold it right there!
Wait!
You think you can get away from me?!
Don't worry about us, just run!
Hurry, run away on your own!
Mokku, don't worry about us!
Hold it, damn it!
I'm sorry we ran away!
Hey, get back here!
Ah, he's coming!
Wait! Wait, wait, wait, hold on!
Hold on, you little brat!
Hold on—you little punk!
Got you now!
- No... help me!
- Begging won't save you!
Help me!
Why do I have to suffer like this?
Because I'm a puppet...
I hate this... Being a puppet...
I want to become human.
I want to become human!
Mokku, I am the Fairy of the
Oak Tree, your birthplace.
Oh, then you're the one
who brought me to life!
I don't want to be a puppet anymore.
I want to become human!
I do not possess that power.
What? Then I can never become human?
You can.
Mokku, becoming human
is entirely up to you.
What should I do? Please, tell me!
Always be a good boy.
If you have a righteous and kind heart,
you will surely become human.
Really?
It is true. You must always strive
to have a good and kind heart.
I'll try my best to have a good, kind heart.
And I'll definitely become human.
I'll be looking forward to that day, Mokku.
Goodbye, Mokku.
A good heart, a kind heart...
Mokku, won't you ever come back home to me?
I could never make another you again.
Grandpa!
Was I just hearing things?
Mokku!
Grandpa!
Grandpa, I'm sorry. I'll be a good boy.
I'll become human. I'll go to school, too.
Mokku... Mokku...
I'm off!
All right.
Grandpa, I'm heading out!
Take care.
Go straight to school, now.
You're called Mokku, aren't you?
I know a really fun place.
Really?
Come on, let's go together!
Mokku, it's such a wonderful place.
Hmph! No way!
Hey! Wait for me!
Mokku and Grandfather
live very happily together.
However...
...because Grandfather
dotes on Mokku so much...
...Redbeard the mouse, who lived
there first, grows jealous.
And then...
...scheming with Kenken
the fox and his gang...
...Redbeard pushes Mokku into the river.
After swallowing so much freezing river
water, will Mokku be able to revive?
Look forward to next week's
Kashi no Ki Mokku!